Kasun Siriwardhana





I am a pending graduate with a background in Electronic and Telecommunication engineering, interested in electronics designs, embedded systems, firmware development, robotics, AI ,automotive electronics, IoT and researching. I possess a strong desire to constantly learn and improve, and thrive in challenging environments. I am a proficient painter capable of creating stunning and captivating artwork and a nature photographer.



Skills

Programming

Electronics Design

Embedded Systems

Firmware Development

Mathematics

Testing and Debugging

Documentation

Autodesk Eagle

Solidworks

Adobe CC

Figma

Python(Intermediate)

C/C++(Intermediate)

Verilog/VHDL(Beginner)

Honors and Awards

IEEEXtreme programming competition 16.0 Semi -Finalist - HackX 2022 (InterUniversity

Start-up Challenge)

Semi -Finalist - IEEE Innovation Nation Sri Lanka (INSL) 2022

Side projects

Off-grid solar installation CCTV system Installation

Publications

DEVELOPMENT OF AN INTELLIGENT OUTDOOR CAMERA SABOTAGE DETECTION MODEL

Co-Author | 2023 16th International Research Conference

Education

KDU

BSc (Hons) in Electronic and Telecommunication Engineering

General Sir John Kotelawala Defence University

Jan 2020 - Jan 2024

Experience

Vega Innovations - Trainee Electronic Engineer

Oct 2022 - Apr 2023

During my tenure at VEGA, I led research on an OTA firmware update project utilizing MQTT and CAN communication protocols for industrial microcontrollers. I also designed a PCB for a home battery pack display driver IC and created a corresponding library.

MQTT, CAN, SPI, UART, FreeRTOS, IoT, TI,ST&ESP32 microcontrollers, PCB design and fabrication

Research Incharge

Oct 2021 - 2022

KDU: Electronic, Robotics and Innovation Club (ERIC)

I have led research, organized events, and enhanced collaboration within the Electronic, Robotics, and Innovations Club. I have forged partnerships, demonstrated expertise, and mentored members, fostering knowledge sharing.

Projects

IMPLEMENTATION OF AN OUTDOOR CAMERA SABOTAGE

DETECTION SYSTEM MODEL - Final Year group project

Transfer Learning, Python, RTSP, Firebase, OOP, Vuejs, Jetson Nano Mar 2023 - Dec 2023

COLD BOX FOR VACCINE TRANSPORTATION - individual project

A cost-effective, user friendly temperature controlling cold box to transport vaccines to upgrade the child vaccination programs in Sri Lanka

2021

IOT GAS LEVEL MONITORING SYSTEM - individual project

HTTP POST Request Method, ESP32, Firebase, Espressif-IDE

This IoT project offers seamless LP gas cylinder monitoring through Wi-Fi connectivity. It ensures secure data storage and real-time notifications in a user-friendly interface,

2023

DESIGNING AN ANIMAL REPELLANT - group(EDP module)

Orcad, Solidworks

2022

References

Prof. TL Weerawardane

Dean Faculty of Engineering, General Sir John Kotelawala Defence University

tlw@kdu.ac.lk

+94 77 444 1419

Dr. SK Wijayasekara,

Assistant Professor,

Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology

sanika.w@sliit.lk

+94 71 907 0666